Finding Aid for the James B. Coover Collection of Jazz Recordings, circa 1950-1957
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
James B. Coover Collection of Jazz Recordings, circa 1950-1957
Mus. Arc. 65
Coover, James, 1925-2004
2 boxes (84 10-inch sound recordings)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
The collection contains 84 10-inch sound recordings of jazz, blues, ragtime, and boogie woogie.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Gift of James B. Coover, 1996.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Biographical Note
James B. Coover (1925-2004) served as Director of the Music Library at the State University of New York at Buffalo 1967-1999. During that time he was responsible for building a major research collection from almost nothing. Jazz was one of his many interests and his love of the music is reflected in this collection of rarer early recordings.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains 84 10-inch sound recordings of various types of jazz and blues music issued in the 1950s. It includes many of the most prominent jazz musicians, including Louis Armstrong, Jack Teagarden, Miles Davis, Bix Beiderbecke, Dizzy Gillespie, Jelly Roll Morton, Stan Getz, Gerry Mulligan, Chet Baker, and many others.
Arrangement
The collection is alphabetically arranged by manufacturer label name and then in manufacturer's number.
Container List
- Allegro: 4032, 1954, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, monaural; Gillespie, Dizzy, 1917-1993 Album title: Dizzy Gillespie and His Orchestra / Dizzy Gillespie (Box 1, Item 01)
  Contents: I waited for you -- Salt peanuts -- A hand fulla gimme -- Ray's idea -- Our delight -- Good dues blues -- That's Earl Brother -- Oop bob Sh'bam
- Allegro: 4049, 1954, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, monaural; Wiley, Lee Album title: Lee Wiley sings / Lee Wiley and Lennie Tristano Performer(s): Lee Wiley; Lennie Tristano (Box 1, Item 02)
  Contents: But not for me -- Sugar -- Woman alone with the blues -- Memories of you -- Supersonic -- on a planet -- Air pocket -- Celestia
- Atlantic: ALS 133, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Meade Lux Lewis' interpretations of the great boogie woogie styles (Box 1, Item 03)
  Contents: Yancey special -- Pinetop's boogie woogie -- Mr. Freddie's blues -- Jumpin' for Pete -- Suitcase blues -- Albert's blues -- Cow Cow blues -- Honkey tonk train blues
- Atlantic: ALS 11237--ALS 11238, 1950-1959, 1 10-inch sound recording; analog, 33 1/3 rpm;; Hines, Earl, 1903-1983 Album title: Piano solo Performer(s): Earl Hines, piano (Box 1, Item 04)
  Contents: Chicago high life -- Just too soon -- Our Monday date -- Off time blues -- Panther rag -- Chimes in blues -- Stowaway -- Blues in thirds
- Atlantic: LP 130, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Yancey special: the last recordings of the late Jimmy Yancey Performer(s): Jimmy Yancey, piano; Mama Yancey, vocals; Israel Crosby, bass (Box 1, Item 05)
  Contents: How long blues -- Make me a pallet on the floor -- Monkey woman blues -- Four o'clock blues -- Sante Fe blues -- Yancey special
- Bethlehem: BCP 1011, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Pete Brown Sextette Performer(s): Pete Brown, alto sax; Joe Wilder, trumpet; Wallie Richardson, guitar; Wade Legge, piano; Gene Ramey, bass; Rudy Collins, drums (Box 1, Item 06)
  Contents: There will never be another you -- I can't believe you're in love with me -- Used blues -- Moonlight in Vermont -- The world is waiting for the sunrise -- Tea for two -- Delta blues
- Bethlehem: BCP-1014, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Jonah Jones Sextette Performer(s): Jonah Jones, trumpet; Vic Dickenson, Urbie Green, trombone; Edmond Hall, clarinet; George Clark, tenor sax; Milt Hinton, Pops Foster, bass; Osie Johnson, drums; Ken Kersey, piano (Box 1, Item 07)
  Contents: Beale street blues -- Down by the riverside -- European blues -- The Sheik of Araby -- You're the cream in my coffee -- Wrap your troubles in dreams -- J. J. special -- Stars fell on Alabama
- Bethlehem: BCP 1017, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Stan Levey plays the compositions of Bill Holman, Bob Cooper and Jimmy Giuffre Performer(s): Stan Levey, drums; Zoot Sims, tenor; Jimmy Giuffre, baritone; Conti Candoli, trumpet; Max Bennett, bass; Claude Williamson, piano (Box 1, Item 08)
  Contents: Exaktamo -- Extraversion -- Drum sticks -- Lightnin' bug -- West coasting -- Fast clip
- Bethlehem: BCP-1019, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Basically, Duke Performer(s): Oscar Pettiford, bass; Clarke Terry, Joe Wilder, trumpet; Jimmy Cleveland, trombone; Jimmy Hamilton, clarinet; Dave Schildkraut, alto; Danny Bank, baritone sax; Earl Knight, piano (Box 1, Item 09)
  Contents: Jack the bear -- Tamalpais -- Swing until the girls come home -- Mood indigo -- Chuckles -- Time on my hands
- Bethlehem: BCP-1040, 1950-1959, 1 10-inch sound recording; 33 1/3 rpm, stereophonic; Garcia, Russell Album title: Wigville Performer(s): Russ Garcia, conductor; Russ Cheever, soprano sax; Charlie Mariano, alto sax; Bill Holman, tenor sax; Jimmy Giuffre, baritone sax; Pete Candoli, trumpet; Conte Candoli, trumpet; Max Bennett, bass; Stan Levy, drums (Box 1, Item 10)
  Contents: Rocky road. -- Floating. -- Butter duck. -- Mellow bone. -- Wigville. -- Smogville. -- Livin' it up. -- Love row. -- Lovely one. -- Then the lid blew off
- Blue Note: BLP 5001, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Mellow the mood Performer(s): Ike Quebec; Ben Webster; John Hardee; Buck Clayton; Jonah Jones; Tyree Glenn; Benny Morton; Barney Bigard; Edmond Hall; Ram Ramirez; Meade Lux Lewis; Charlie Christian; Tiny Grimes; Oscar Pettiford; Milton Hinton; Israel Crosby; Sidney Catlett; J.C. Heard (Box 1, Item 11)
  Contents: I surrender dear -- Sweet and lovely -- If I had you -- Profoundly blue -- She's funny that way -- My old flame -- Blue Harlem
- Blue Note: BLP 5002, 1950-1959, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, monaural; Monk, Thelonious Album title: Genius of modern music / Thelonious Monk Performer(s): Thelonious Monk, piano; others: George Taitt; Edmund Gregory; Milton Jackson; Robert Paige; Gene Ramey; John Simmons; Art Blakey; Shadow Wilson; Idresse Suliman; Danny Quebec West; Billy Smith (Box 1, Item 12)
  Contents: 'Round about midnight -- Off minor -- Ruby my dear -- I mean you -- Thelonious -- Epistrophy -- Well you needn't -- Mysterioso
- Blue Note: BLP 5003, 1950-1959, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, monaural; Powell, Bud Album title: Amazing Bud Powell / Bud Powell Performer(s): Bud Powell, piano; others: Fats Navarro; Sonny Rollins; Curly Russell; Tommy Potter; Max Roach; Roy Haynes (Box 1, Item 13)
  Contents: Un poco loco / Powell -- Over the rainbow / Harburg - Arlen -- Ornithology / Harris -- Wail / Powell -- A night in Tunisia / Robin - Gillespie -- It could happen to you / Burke - Van Heusen -- You go to my head / Coots - Gillespie -- Bouncing with Bud / Powell
- Blue Note: BLP 5013, 1950-1959, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, monaural; Davis, Miles Album title: Young man with a horn / Miles Davis Performer(s): Miles Davis, trumpet; others: Jay Jay Johnson; Jackie McLean; Gil Coggins; Oscar Pettiford; Kenny Clarke (Box 1, Item 14)
  Contents: Dear old Stockholm / Varmeland -- Would'n you / Gillespie -- Yesterdays / Kern - Harbach -- Chance it / Pettiford -- Donna / McClean -- How deep is the ocean / Berlin
- Blue Note: BLP 5033, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Gil Mellé Quintet: with Urbie Green and Tal Farlow volume 2 Performer(s): Gil Mellé, tenor and baritone sax; Urbie Green, trombone; Tal Farlow, guitar; Clyde Lombardi, bass; Joe Morello, drums (Box 1, Item 15)
  Contents: Timepiece -- Lover man -- Gingersnap -- A lion lives here -- Spellbound -- Transition
- Blue Note: BLP 7009, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Giant of Jazz / Sidney Bechet and his Blue Note Jazz Men Performer(s): "Wild Bill" Davison; Ray Diehl; Sidney Bechet; Art Hodes; Walter Page; "Slick" Jones; Fred Moore; Claude Luter (Box 1, Item 16)
  Contents: Jazz band ball -- Tin roof blues -- Cake walking babies -- Temptation rag -- When the saints go marching in -- Basin Street blues -- Tiger rag -- Riverboat shuffle
- Blue Note: BLP 7010, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: George Lewis and his New Orleans Stompers Performer(s): Avery "Kid" Howard; Jim Robinson; George Lewis; Lawrence Marrero; Chester Zardis; Edgar Mosley (Box 1, Item 17)
  Contents: Climaz Rag -- Dauphine Street blues -- Just a closer walk with thee -- Fidgety feet -- Deep bayou blues -- Milenberg joys
- Blue Note: BLP 7017, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Albert Ammons: memorial album Performer(s): Meade Lux Lewis, piano (Box 1, Item 18)
  Contents: Boogie woogie stomp -- Boogie woogie blues -- Bass goin' crazy -- Twos and fews -- Chicago in mind -- Suitcase blues
- Brunswick: BL 58002, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Ellingtonia volume 1: a collection of distinctive recordings / played by Duke Ellington and his orchestra (Box 1, Item 19)
  Contents: East St. Louis toodle-oo -- Birmingham breakdown -- Rockin' in rhythm -- Twelfth street rag -- Black and tan fantasy -- The mooche -- Mood indigo -- Wall street wail
- Brunswick: BL 58003, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Boogie woogie piano: a collection of rare recordings by the originator of boogie woogie / Pine Top Smith; A King of the piano: in a collection of rare piano solo recordings volume 1 / Jelly Roll Morton (Box 1, Item 20)
  Contents: Pinetop's boogie woogie; Pinetop's blues; Jump steady blues; I'm sober now -- King Porter stomp; The Pearls; Frog I more rag; Fat meat and greens
- Brunswick: BL 58004, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Jazz classics / Louis Armstrong Performer(s): Louis Armstrong with: Johnny Dodds' Black Bottom Stompers; Lill's Hot Shots; Erskine Tate's Vendome Orchestra; Red Onion Jazz Babies (Box 1, Item 21)
  Contents: Wild man blues -- Melancholy -- Georgia bo bo -- Drop that sack -- Static strut -- Stomp off, let's go! -- Terrible blues -- Santa Claus blues
- Brunswick: BL 58018, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Boogie woogie piano: historic recordings by pioneer piano men Performer(s): Montana Taylor; Speckled Red; Romeo Nelson; Cow Cow Davenport (Box 1, Item 22)
  Contents: Detroit rocks -- Indian Avenue stomp -- The dirty dozen no. 1 & 2 -- Head rag hop -- Wilkins Street stomp -- Cow Cow blues -- State Street
- Brunswick: BL 58022, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Barrel house piano: eight authentic solos by acknowledged masters of the style Performer(s): Frank Melrose; James P. Johnson; Mary Lou Williams; Alex Hill (Box 1, Item 23)
  Contents: Pass the jug -- Jelly Roll stomp -- Jingels -- You've got to be modernistic -- Drag 'em -- Night life -- Stompin' 'em down -- Tack head blues
- Brunswick: BL 58024, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Harlem jazz 1930: selected performances by the first great swing bands Performer(s): Duke Ellington; Don Redman; Fletcher Henderson; Luis Russell (Box 1, Item 24)
  Contents: Double check stomp -- Jolly wog -- Chant of the weed -- Shakin' the African -- Radio rhythm -- Just blues -- Saratoga drag -- Case on dawn
- Brunswick: BL 58026, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Riverboat jazz: New Orleans to Chicago :as played by the famous jazzmen on the Mississippi Performer(s): King Oliver; Dewey Jackson; Jelly Roll Morton; Jimmy Wade; Punch Miller; Albert Wynn (Box 1, Item 25)
  Contents: Snag it -- Capitol blues -- Mr. Jelly Lord -- Midnight mama -- Gates blues -- Parkway stomp -- Down by the levee -- She's cryin' for me
- Brunswick: BL 58037, 1950-1959, 1 10-inch sound recording; analog, 33 1/3 rpm;; Album title: Battle of jazz: volume 1 Performer(s): On side 1: Bud Freeman, tenor sax, and the Summa cum Laude Orchestra (Max Kaminsky, trumpet; Brad Gowans, trombone; Pee Wee Russell, clarinet; Dave Bowman, piano; Eddie Condon, guitar; Clyde Newcomb, bass; Al Sidell, drums); on side 2: Joe Marsala, clarinet, and his orchestra (Marty Marsala, trumpet; Ben Glassman, alto sax; John Smith, tenor sax; Adele Girard, harp; Dave Bowman, piano; Carmen Mastren, guitar; Jack Kelleher, bass; Shelly Manne, drums) (Box 1, Item 26)
  Contents: The sail fish / Bud Freeman -- As long as I live; Harold Arlen; Ted Koehler -- Sunday / Ned Miller; Chester Conn; Jules Stein; Bennie Krueger -- Satanic blues / Larry Shields; Emile Christian -- Bulls eye; Lower register / Adele Girard -- Slow down / Redd Evans -- I know that you know / Vincent Youmans; Anne Caldwell
- Capitol: H-383, 1956?, 1 10-inch sound recording; analog, 33 1/3 rpm;; Album title: New concepts of artistry in rhythm Performer(s): Stan Kenton and his orchestra (Box 1, Item 27)
  Contents: 23°N - 82°W -- Portrait of a count -- Improvisation -- Invention for guitar and trumpet -- My lady -- Young blood -- Frank speaking
- Capitol: H 439, 19–, 1 10-inch sound recording; 33 1/3 rpm, monaural;; Mulligan, Gerry Album title: Gerry Mulligan and his ten-tette Performer(s): Gerry Mulligan, baritone sax, piano; Chet Baker, Pete Candoli, trumpet; John Graas, horn; Bud Shank, alto sax; Bob Enevoldsen, trombone; Ray Siegel, tuba; Joe Mondragon, bass; Chico Hamilton or Larry Bunker, drums (Box 1, Item 28)
  Contents: Rocker--Walking shoes--Simbah--Ontet--Westwood walk--Ballad--Taking a chance on love--Flash
- Clef: MG C-116, 1951?, 1 10-inch sound recording; analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural;; Oscar Peterson Quartet Album title: The Oscar Peterson Quartet Performer(s): Jazz quartets; Peterson, piano; Barney Kessel, guitar; Ray Brown, bass; Alvin Stoller, drums (Box 1, Item 29)
  Contents: The Astaire blues -- Stompin' at the Savoy
- Columbia: CL 6052, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Goodman sextet session / Benny Goodman Sextet (Box 1, Item 30)
  Contents: Tiger rag -- Ain't misbehavin' -- She's funny that way -- I got rhythm -- Just one of those things -- China boy -- Shine -- Rachel's dream
- Columbia: CL 6187, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Freddy Gardner Performer(s): Peter Yorke & his orchestra (Box 1, Item 31)
  Contents: I'm in the mood for love -- Valse vanite -- These foolish things -- Roses of Picardy -- Body and soul -- I only have eyes for you
- Contemporary: C 2504, 1953, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Dizzy in Paris Performer(s): Dizzy Gillepsie, trumpet; Nat Peck, trombone; Wade Legge, piano; Lou Hackney, bass; Al Jones, drums (Box 1, Item 32)
  Contents: Mon homme -- Toujours -- C'est comme ça -- 's merveilleux -- Fais gaffe! -- Au pays d'oobladee -- Nocturne lunaire -- J'ai du rhythme
- Contemporary: C2511, 1954, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Manne, Shelly Album title: Shelly Manne and his men, vol. 2 Performer(s): Ollie Mitchell, Don Fagerquist & Shorty Rogers, trumpet; Bob Enevoldsen, trombone; Paul Sarmento, tuba; Russ Freeman & Marty Paich, piano; Joe Mondragon, bass; Shelly Mann, drums (Box 1, Item 33)
  Contents: Dimension in thirds -- Shapes, motion, colors -- Alternation -- Divertimento for brass and rhythm -- Lullaby -- Etude de concert
- Contemporary Records: C2514, 1954, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, monaural; Kessel, Barney Album title: Barney Kessel Performer(s): Barney Kessel; others: Bob Cooper; Claude Williamson; Monty Budwig; Shelly Manne (Box 1, Item 34)
  Contents: Barney's Blues -- A foggy day / George and Ira Gershwin -- Prelude to a kiss / Ellington -- 64 bars on Wilshire -- Speak low / Kurt Weill and Ogden Nash -- Love is here to stay / George and Ira Gershwin -- How long has this been going on / George and Ira Gershwin -- On a slow boat to China / Frank Loesser
- Contemporary: C2516, 1955, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Manne, Shelly Album title: Shelly Manne: "The Three" Performer(s): Shelly Manne, drums; Shorty Rogers, trumpet; Jimmy Giuffre, clarinet, tenor & baritone saxes (Box 1, Item 35)
  Contents: Flip -- Autumn in New York -- Pas de trois -- Three on a row -- Steeplechase -- Abstract no. 1
- EmArcy: MG 26005, 1952, 1 10-inch sound recording; analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Vaughan, Sarah, 1924-1990 Album title: Images / Sarah Vaughan (Box 1, Item 36)
  Contents: Lover man -- Shulie a bop -- Polka dots and moonbeams -- Body and soul -- They can't take that away from me -- Prelude to a kiss -- You hit the spot -- If I knew then (What I know now)
- EmArcy: MG 26041, 1950-1959, 1 10-inch sound recording; analog, 33 1/3 rpm;; Lars Gullin Quartet Album title: Lars Gullin Quartet Performer(s): Lars Gullin, baritone sax; Rolf Berg, guitar; George Riedel, bass; Robert Edman, drums (Box 1, Item 37)
  Contents: Danny's dream -- Be careful -- Igloo -- Circus
- EmArcy: MG 26043, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Clifford Brown and Max Roach (Box 1, Item 38)
  Contents: Delilah -- Parisian thoroughfare -- Däähoud -- Joy spring -- Jordu
- Epic: LG-1010, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Moder woodwind expressions / the Harris-Leigh Woodwinds (Box 1, Item 39)
  Contents: Burlesque -- Ceres -- Spooks -- Blues -- Sudden change -- Horn song -- Waltz for an insane puppet -- Mambo diablo
- Good Time Jazz: L-10-L-11, 1953, 2 10-inch sound recordings; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Kid Ory's Creole Jazz Band volume 1 & 2 Performer(s): Kid Ory, trombone; Mutt Carey, trumpet; Omer Simeon & Darnell Howard, clarinet; Bud Scott, guitar; Buster Wilson, piano; Ed Garland, bass; Minor Hall & Alton Redd, drums (Box 1, Item 40-41)
  Contents: Creole song -- Get out of here -- Blues for Jimmie Noone -- South -- Panama -- Under the bamboo tree -- Careless love -- Do what Ory say -- Maryland, my Maryland -- Down home rag -- 1919 rag -- Oh! Didn't he ramble -- Ory's creole trombone -- Weary blues -- Maple leaf rag -- Original dixieland one step
- Jazztone: J-SPEC-100, 1955, 1 10-inch sound recording; analog, 33 1/3 rpm;; Album title: Jazz sampler Performer(s): Various performers (Box 1, Item 42)
  Contents: Jelly roll blues (Sidney Bechet and his New Orleans Feetwarmers) -- Slam slam blues (Red Norvo All-Stars) -- Relaxin' at Camarillo (Charlie Parker All-Stars) -- Dark eyes (Art Tatum Trio) -- B.C. blues (Buck Clayton Quintet) -- Honeysuckle rose (Coleman Hawkins Quartet) -- Serenade to a Shylock (Jack Teagarden and his orchestra) -- Trio (Erroll Garner Trio) -- Moon burns (Woody Herman Woodchoppers) -- Basin Street blues (Rex Stewart and his Dixieland Jazz Band)
- MGM: E-523, 1957?, 1 10-inch sound recording; analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural;; Eckstine, Billy Album title: Songs by Billy Eckstine (Box 1, Item 43)
  Contents: Temptation -- Over the rainbow -- My old flame -- Someone to watch over me -- Fools rush in -- Nobody knows the trouble I've seen -- You go to my head -- I don't want to cry any more
- Norgran Records: MG –2, 1950-1959, 1 10-inch sound recording; analog, 33 1/3 rpm;; Currently missing: November 20 2013. Album title: The Dizzy Gillespie Stan Getz Sextet Performer(s): Performed by the Dizzy Gillespie Stan Getz Sextet (Box 1, Item 44)
  Contents: It don't mean a thing -- Let a song go out of my heart -- Exactly like you -- Talk of the town
- Norgran: MG –27, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Chico mambo dance session / Chico O'Farrill (Box 1, Item 45)
  Contents: No te importe saber -- Vaya con dios -- Pianarabatibri -- L. A. mambo -- Quiéreme mucho -- More mambo -- Mambo for bunto -- Botellero
- Norgran: MG –28, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Chico O'Farrill's Latino dance session (Box 1, Item 46)
  Contents: Lamento -- You stepped out of a dream -- Cachita -- Rumbonsito -- Munequita Linda -- Siboney -- Angels flight -- Tres palabras
- Pacific Jazz: PJ LP-1, 1950-1959, 1 10-inch sound recording; 33 1/3 rpm; Gerry Mulligan Quartet Album title: Pacific Jazz presents the Gerry Mulligan Quartet Performer(s): Gerry Mulligan, baritone saxophone; Chet Baker, trumpet; Chico Hamilton, drums; Bob Whitlock, bass (Box 1, Item 47)
  Contents: Frenesi--Freeway--Soft shoe--Aren't you glad you're you--Bernie's tune--Walkin' shoes--Nights at the turntable--Lullaby of the leaves
- Pacific Jazz: PJ LP-6, 1950-1959, 1 10-inch sound recording; analog, 33 1/3 rpm;; Album title: Pacific Jazz presents the Chet Baker Quartet Performer(s): Performed by the Chet Baker Quartet; featuring Russ Freeman (Box 1, Item 48)
  Contents: No ties -- Band aid -- The thrill is gone -- All the things you are -- Long ago and far away -- Happy little sunbeam -- Moon love -- Bea's flat
- Period: SPL 1105, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Spring sequence / Ralph Burns and his ensemble (Box 1, Item 49)
  Contents: Springs sequence -- It might as well be Spring -- Spring is here -- Sprang -- Echo of Spring
- Period: SPL 1108, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Osie's oasis Performer(s): Osie Johnson and his combos (Box 1, Item 50)
  Contents: The desert song -- Cokernut tree -- Jumpin' at the waterhole -- Blues for the camels -- Osi's Oasis -- Midnight mirage
- Period: SPL 1109, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Bijou Performer(s): Ralph Burns and his ensemble (Box 1, Item 51)
  Contents: Bijou -- Gina -- Perpetual motion -- Lover come back to me -- Autobahn blues -- Spring in Naples
- Period: SPL 1110, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Original Dixieland / Jack Teagarden and his orchestra Performer(s): Jack Teagarden and his orchestra (Box 1, Item 52)
  Contents: Original Dixieland one step -- Riverboat shuffle -- King Porter stomp -- High society -- Eccentric -- Milenberg joys
- Period: SPL 1111, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Jazzical moods, volume 2 Performer(s): Charles Mingus, piano; Oliver King, trumpet; John La Porta, alto sax; Teo Macero, tenor sax; Jackson Wiley, cello; Clem DeRosa, drums (Box 1, Item 53)
  Contents: The spur of the moment -- Echonitus -- Thrice upon a theme -- Four hands
- Period: SPL 1112, undated, 1 10-inch sound recording; Analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural; Album title: Johnson's Whacks / Osie Johnson and his combos Performer(s): Osie Johnson Sextet; Osie Johnson Quintet (Box 1, Item 54)
  Contents: Cat walk -- I don't want to cry anymore -- Don't hug me -- Johnson's whacks -- Flute to boot -- Osmosis
- Prestige: PRLP 160, 1955?, 1 10-inch sound recording; analog, 33 1/3 rpm, monaural;; Album title: The Modern Jazz Quartet Performer(s): Jazz quartet: Milt Jackson, vibes; John Lewis, piano; Percy Heath, bass; Kenny Clarke, drums (Box 1, Item 55)